Guide to the Stanford University, Alliance for Lifelong Learning, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Alliance for Lifelong Learning, records
1996-2002
SC1196
Stanford University. Alliance for Lifelong Learning.
3.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Access Terms
Alumni Activities; Stanford alumni; Stanford University--Alumni--Reminiscences.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Stanford University: The University Alliance for Life Long Learning (documentation) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History of Nature, course guidebook, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The West: Presence of the Past, course guidebook, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Encountering Homer's Odyssey, course guidebook, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Power of Forgiveness, seminar packet (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Nuclear, Biological and Chemical Weapons: The New Realities, seminar packet (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - World War II and the World it Made, course guidebook, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Audiovisual materials
  - The Renaissance and the Discovery of the Modern World [VHS Tape], 1989; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - History of Nature Marsh: Dominion Over Nature, 2002; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Presents Technology and You, 1998 Oct; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - History of Nature Thoreau: Transcending Nature, 2002; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - History of Nature Aristotle: The Soul of Nature, 2002; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - History of Nature Carson: Kinship with Nature, 2002; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - To Touch History: Gorbachev at Stanford, 1990; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - History of Nature Darwin: The Indifference of Nature, 2002; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - World War II and the World it Made, 2001; 10 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 2)
  - Seizing Power The Steel Seizure Case Revisited, 2003; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2)
  - Homecoming/Class of 61 Panel, 10/13/2006; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Pigott Theater Panel, 2006 Oct; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Milani, 10/13/2006; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Rm 530-127, 10/12/2006; 2 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Hanushek, Eric, 10/12/2006; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - "The Legacy of Rome" Anthony Raubitschek, undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Am. West Pt 2. Inventing Buffalo Bill/Jackson Turner [Richard White], 1999; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Day 1 - Soul, undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - "The Experimental Novel in the Modern World" William M. Chace, undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Class of 72, 10/18/2002; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - "Russia and Europe" Terrence Emmons, undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Naimark, Norman M., 10/12/2006; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - "The Renaissance and the Discovery of the Modern World" Lawrence V. Ryan, undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - RH - Class of 92 10th Year Reunion Panel, 10/18/2002; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - "The Novel as Art and Insight" Albert J. Guerard, undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Kimball, 10/12/2006; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Day 3 - Soul, undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Room 320-105 Alumni Association One Book Discussion, 10/19/2002; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - "The European View of America" J. Martin Evans, undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Ann Aud Class of 86, 10/13/2006; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Cantor Aud Class of 51, 10/13/2006; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - David Kennedy on "The West", undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - "The Age of Reason and Enlightenment" Carolyn Lougee, undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Class of 1976 Rm 040, 10/13/2006; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 2)
  - The West Presence of the Past, 2002; 6 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 3)
  - Panel of Experts Pigott Theater, 10/12/2006; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 3)
  - Bettinger Daly/Matson - Conservation Firth Murray McFaul Packer/Lyman at Pigott, 10/12/2006; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 3)
  - Dill AR2, 10/13/2006; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 3)
  - Eaton .wav file, 10/13/2006; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 3)
  - Nancy Packer Stanford Book Salon Stegner, 10/15/2006; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 3)
  - Milani - The Future of Democracy in Iran, 10/13/2006; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 3)
  - Gerritsen, 10/12/2006; 2 optical disc(s) (CD); 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 3)
  - CWOQ Steve Sano, 10/13/2006; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 3)
  - 3 books, 9/20/2006; 2 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 3)
  - Hanushek - Improving California Schools, 10/12/2006; 2 optical disc(s) (CD); 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 3)
  - Cardinal Society Luncheon, 10/15/2006; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 3)
  - Stanford University Encountering Homer's Odyssey, 2001; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-ROM) (Box 3)
  - Class of 2003 Senior Class Slideshow, 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R); 1 optical disc(s) (CD-ROM) (Box 3)
  - Hear at Stanford Audio Magazine Volume 1, 2000; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 3)
  - Naimark, Norman M. 50 Years of Stanford Overseas, 10/12/2006; 2 optical disc(s) (CD); 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 3)
  - Bill Chace Experimental Novel - Ulysses "Not Since Shakespeare", 1988; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Richard Rodriguez, undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #1 S.A.C. J Gibbs "Viewing the African Mosaic", 8/5/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #2 S.A.C. K Jackson "An African Society Remembers Its Past", 8/5/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #4 S.A.C. Duignan "The West's Impact of Africa: The Erosion of Isolationism", 8/6/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #5 S.A.C. J Gibbs "Traditional African Political Thought", 8/6/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #7 S.A.C. D Abernathy "American Political Thought in the Colonial Era", 8/7/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #8 Duignan "Acceleration of the Pace of Change", 8/7/2978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #9 S.A.C. Greenberg "Language Problems of Africa", 8/7/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - #10 S.A.C. J Gibbs "Traditional Religious Thought and Symbolism", 8/8/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #11 S.A.C. D. Abernathy "Political Thought in South Africa", 8/8/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #12B S.A.C. PANEL Discussion of South Africa Cont., 8/8/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #12A S.A.C. PANEL Discussion of South Africa, 8/8/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #13 S.A.C. Duignan, 8/9/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #14 S.A.C. Duignan, 8/9/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - #17 SAC D Abernethy "Confronting the Challenges of Political Independence", 8/10/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - #20 S.A.C. J Gibbs "The Cultural Context of Everyday African Thought", 8/11/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - #21 S.A.C. K Jackson "Post World War II Developments Among African Intellectuals and Writers", 8/11/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #22A S.A.C. St. Clair Drake "Independence or Dependence" Discussant Hans Weiler, 8/11/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #22B S.A.C. St. Clair Drake "Independence or Dependence" Discussant Hans Weiler, 8/11/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - #23 S.A.C. D Abernethy "The Leader as Teacher: Nyerere", 8/12/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - #24 S.A.C. K Jackson "Roots and Africa: The New World and Old World Dialectic", 8/12/1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - White, Richard, undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - David Kennedy Portrait of a Lady American Character, 1988; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Lyman Award copy, 1/21/2004; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Martin Evans Europeans on America, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Lynman Award Tape #1 Master, 1/21/2004; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Tape #2 Copy, undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - N/A, undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Jim Sheehan French Revolution, 1988; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Palumbo-Liu, David, undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
- Audiovisual materials, Accession ARCH-2015-010
  - World War II and the World It Made, 2001; 4 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)